there are a lot of reasons that I choose
Final Cut Pro to edit all my videos I
mean most people know that it's really
fast and the interface is intuitive so
it's quick to learn but I think often
people underwrite how powerful it is
part of the reason is that it really
gets more powerful once you get a few
key plugins so in this video I'm going
to show you how I used some of my
favorites subscribers I've definitely
seen them before you probably didn't
even realize there were plugins they're
all from motion VFX I've been using
their stuff for a long time they have a
ton of incredible products and this
isn't a sponsored video I was talking to
them about some of the plugins that I
love and they offered to put them all
together into a set so I will get some
commissions if you click on the link in
the description below but otherwise
hopefully you just find something useful
here let's start with one that'd be
perfect for the kind of video making
right now M tutorial so it's got all the
things that will help guide your viewer
through the instructions you're giving
on screen there are so many in here I'm
not going to be able to go through all
of them just a few that I do use a good
example here is click and you can see
how easy it is to click and drag it into
the timeline a blank screen recording
without guidance is is hard to follow so
I'm just going to grab this little
cursor move it on top of my real cursor
and when I play it back boom you can
tell exactly where I clicked and there's
a few others like arrows that can
emphasize movement there's also a bunch
of helpful ways to highlight the frame
like I like this scribbly highlighter
not only can you position it to be on
the part of the screen that you want but
each of The Strokes you can move around
so it has a custom look to it as well
can I tell you a secret a lot of the
most powerful plugins are pretty subtle
so this Zoom effect I use all the time
you just drag the title onto your
timeline and I'm going to combine it
with a highlight here in this shot I'm
trying to draw attention to how long the
processing takes I'll put the Highlight
on top of the progress bar and I'm going
to zoom in and position it right over
the Highlight so we watch a playback you
can see how long it takes for a pixel 7
Pro to process a portrait mode photo a
little longer than I'd like but it
really clearly guides the eye where to
look and with a lot of these plugins you
can turn on and off animate in and
animate out so I could start the zoom in
the middle of a shot and then end the
shot before zooming out out so that we
just stay zoomed in you don't always
need to both move in and out another
useful way to highlight things is the
selection line I'll start by making it
my usual yellow make the line fatter and
then I can actually change the exact
shape of How It's circling things but I
can give it a kind of hand-drawn look so
it doesn't have to be a perfect circle
it can kind of be around the shape of
the area we want to look at I can add a
description in this case there's already
text on screen so I don't need it and if
I want it to look more handwritten I can
turn off closed lines and just manually
move these exactly where I want them to
be oh and it's important to put it under
this Zoom layer so that as I zoom in it
looks like I'm zooming in on the
handwriting that's happening and it all
clicks together I can usually put these
subtle looks to use in every video I
make but let's take a look at some
Bolder plugins next is m music video and
obviously this is for anybody that
shoots music videos there's a ton of
stuff in here like some great typography
for opening titles
or closing credits okay but let's
stylize this a bit let's add a burn
effect
for these first two shots you can
quickly add a letterbox which animates
in and kind of gives you a cinematic
aspect ratio in just a few seconds and
if you don't have an anamorphic lens you
can add one in post
but you know what keeps me coming back
to a music video The subtle effects
there's actually some really great ones
in here too zoom in and zoom out are
some of my favorites it also comes with
some basic transitions so instead of a
hard cut I can drop this on make it a
little shorter and then we get this
crazy Digital Dissolve but I'm telling
you it's a subtle effects that are the
most useful so let's use zoom out I'll
put this at the start of the clip and it
gives us a continuous zoom out so what
we get now is a match cut and then
pulling out to see all of the specs
about these two cell phones of course
you can do zooms with keyframes in Final
Cut but it's way slower to do and also
keyframe support isn't great and Final
Cut it could be a lot better so I really
like dropping these on and this shot
leads us to our next plugins let's take
a look at M features if you talk about
products or anything with specs or
benchmarks these are perfect for you
there's just a whole bunch of basically
comparisons between different products
advantages disadvantages just a whole
bunch of ways of displaying data without
spending any time laying it out yourself
so I customize these two to have my
channel font they animate in and then on
their own they also animate out so I
don't have to go to all the work of
keyframing and all this other stuff that
motion can handle well Final Cut Pro
can't handle that well and I think a lot
of Premiere editors don't even know you
can do in Final Cut motion VFX also have
a ton of title presets you might have
actually seen some of them in apple
Keynotes one set that I've been using a
lot lately is called M title kinetic 2.
they have pretty simple animations that
are easy to layout easy to work with but
they really look like you put a lot more
work into it so let's just find one that
works we'll drag it over here let's time
it right as he lands
nice change it to my channel font it'll
make it bigger there's already a
gradient here which I really like these
colors they've chosen I don't know we
can just mix them up a little
probably gonna make it worse going so
fast and we get a result that looks like
we put a lot more time into it than we
did by the way here's a little trick if
you're using white text which I do all
the time it can be really helpful to
just make sure that your white point in
Final Cut Pro isn't too high so we could
drag it down a bit in the highlights a
bit in the mid tones and just make sure
that text is visible in my videos I
usually try to have any clipping points
any true white be less than white the
white point should be lower than the
Pure White of the background on your
screen okay one more that's really
useful this is called M counter this is
how I used it in my recent video
comparing the pixel 7 Pro to the iPhone
14 pro you can see it just shows how
long each of them takes so as I go
through the timer keeps going even while
the iPhone on the right is finished the
pixel is still processing but there's a
ton of different formats you can have it
be more of like a progress bar or if
you're running a time lapse you could be
showing the duration of the whole thing
and you can set it over any number range
you could freeze it on a specific number
if you haven't tried to animate numbers
or time in Final Cut Pro before well I
have and take it for me it's miserable
so don't do it just let motion VFX do it
for you each of these plugins can do way
more than enough time to show you in
this video but all of them combined this
set really will make Final Cut Pro way
more powerful so head over to motionbfx
see how they work see what else I didn't
have time to show you today and if you
want to learn more about editing in
Final Cut Pro I've got a whole playlist
for you to watch next I'll see you over
there guys